{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'acquaintance'?", "answer": "знакомство"}
{"question": "How do you say 'arrival' in Russian?", "answer": "приезд"}
{"question": "What is the English translation for 'приветствие'?", "answer": "greeting"}
{"question": "How do you say 'My name is' in Russian?", "answer": "Меня зовут… (Minya zavut…)"}
{"question": "Where did the person come from according to the text?", "answer": "Lebanon (Ливана)"}
{"question": "What language does the person speak according to the text?", "answer": "English (английски)"}
{"question": "Do you speak English?", "answer": "Говорите ли Вы по-английски?"}
{"question": "Very pleased to meet you!", "answer": "Очень рад (рада) с Вами познакомиться!"}
{"question": "Good morning!", "answer": "Доброе утро!"}
{"question": "How do you say 'Good evening!' in Russian?", "answer": "Добрый вечер!"}
{"question": "How do you say 'How are you?' in Russian?", "answer": "Как Вы поживаете?"}
{"question": "How do you say 'Good-bye!' in Russian?", "answer": "До свидания!"}
{"question": "How do you say 'I wish you good luck!' in Russian?", "answer": "Желаю успеха!"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'Have a nice day!'?", "answer": "Хорошего дня!"}
{"question": "What does 'May I come in?' translate to in Russian?", "answer": "Разрешите войти"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'Разрешите …?'", "answer": "Allow...?"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'пожалуйста'?", "answer": "please"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'войти'?", "answer": "enter"}
{"question": "How do you say 'show' in Russian?", "answer": "покажите"}
{"question": "What is the English translation of 'помочь мне'?", "answer": "help me"}
{"question": "Could you provide the transcription for 'проводить меня'?", "answer": "pravadit minya"}
{"question": "What do you want?", "answer": "Что Вы говорите? Shto vi khatitye?"}
{"question": "Can you help me?", "answer": "Можете ли Вы мне помочь? Mogete li vu mne pamoch?"}
{"question": "I have no objection.", "answer": "Не возражаю. Ni-vazrazhayu."}
{"question": "How do you say 'I don’t agree with you' in Russian?", "answer": "Я не согласен в Вами."}
{"question": "What is the Russian phrase for 'Excuse me, please'?", "answer": "Извините, пожалуйста."}
{"question": "How do you express 'Don’t be angry' in Russian?", "answer": "Не сердитесь."}
{"question": "What are some ways to express gratitude in English?", "answer": "help, advice, invitation, attention, congratulations"}
{"question": "How do you say 'Thank you for your help' in Russian?", "answer": "Спасибо за помощь"}
{"question": "Translate the following time units from English to Russian: second, minute, hour, half an hour, week", "answer": "секунда, минута, час, полчаса, неделя"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'half an hour' in Russian?", "answer": "полчаса"}
{"question": "How do you say 'week' in Russian?", "answer": "неделя"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'year' in Russian?", "answer": "год"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'century'?", "answer": "век (vyek)"}
{"question": "How do you say 'morning' in Russian?", "answer": "утро (utra)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'afternoon'?", "answer": "день (dyen)"}
{"question": "What time is it?", "answer": "Который час?"}
{"question": "Nine a.m. (p.m.)", "answer": "Девять часов утра (вечера)."}
{"question": "In five minutes", "answer": "Через пять минут."}
{"question": "What date is it today?", "answer": "Какое сегодня число? Kakoye sivodnya chislo?"}
{"question": "my watch… is slow", "answer": "мои часы… отстают mai chisi… atstayut"}
{"question": "my watch… is fast", "answer": "мои часы… спешат mai chisi… spishat"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'bill'?", "answer": "счет (shchot)"}
{"question": "How do you say 'blanket' in Russian?", "answer": "одеяло (adiyala)"}
{"question": "In Russian, what is the equivalent term for 'doorman'?", "answer": "портье (part’ye)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation and transcription for 'mail'?", "answer": "почта, pochta"}
{"question": "How do you say 'pillow' in Russian and its transcription?", "answer": "подушка, padushka"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation and transcription for 'reservation'?", "answer": "бронь, bron’"}
{"question": "Which is the way to the … hotel?", "answer": "Как проехать в гостиницу …?"}
{"question": "Give me the address of the …hotel, please…", "answer": "Дайте, пожалуйста, адрес гостиницы …"}
{"question": "Мне (нам) нужна гостиница недалеко от центра города.", "answer": "Mnye (nam) nuzna gastinitsa nidaliko at tsentra gorada."}
{"question": "Please, reserve a room at the … hotel.", "answer": "Daytye, pazhalusta, adris gastinitsi"}
{"question": "Have you any accommodation?", "answer": "У вас есть свободные номера?"}
{"question": "My surname is …", "answer": "Моя фамилия …"}
{"question": "What do you say for a single room in Russian?", "answer": "номер для одного"}
{"question": "How do you ask if the room has a bath or shower in Russian?", "answer": "В номере есть ванная (душ)"}
{"question": "How do you inquire about the floor of the room in Russian?", "answer": "На каком этаже этот номер?"}
{"question": "Na kakom etazhe etat nomir?", "answer": "I’d like to have a room upstairs (downstairs)."}
{"question": "Skol’ka stoit etat nomir?", "answer": "How much does this room cost?"}
{"question": "Входит ли завтрак в стоимость номера?", "answer": "Does the price of this room include breakfast?"}
{"question": "Входит ли завтрак в стоимость номера?", "answer": "Fkhodit li zaftrak f stoimas’t nomira?"}
{"question": "May I see this room?", "answer": "Можно посмотреть этот номер? Mozhna pasmatryet’ etat nomir?"}
{"question": "Do you have a … room?", "answer": "Есть ли у вас номер...? Yest’ li u vas nomir ...?"}
{"question": "How do you say 'bigger' and 'smaller' in Russian?", "answer": "побольше (поменьше)"}
{"question": "How do you say 'better' and 'cheaper' in Russian?", "answer": "получше (подешевле)"}
{"question": "Where can you find the currency exchange?", "answer": "Скажите, пожалуйста, где обмен валюты?"}
{"question": "Where can I buy wine?", "answer": "Где можно купить вино?"}
{"question": "Where can I buy fruit?", "answer": "Где можно купить фрукты?"}
{"question": "Where can I buy clothes?", "answer": "Где можно купить одежду?"}
{"question": "Where can I buy sports goods?", "answer": "спорттовары"}
{"question": "How can I get to the cinema?", "answer": "Как доехать до кинотеатра?"}
{"question": "Speak louder, please.", "answer": "Говорите, пожалуйста, громче."}
{"question": "How do you say 'this afternoon' in Russian?", "answer": "сегодня днем"}
{"question": "How do you ask for the bill to be ready in Russian?", "answer": "Приготовьте, пожалуйста, счет."}
{"question": "How do you request a taxi in Russian?", "answer": "Вызовите мне, пожалуйста, такси."}
{"question": "How do you say 'I'll be ready in about five (ten) minutes' in Russian?", "answer": "Я буду готов ( -а) через пять (десять) минут."}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'blood pressure' into Russian?", "answer": "давление"}
{"question": "How do you say 'high pressure' in Russian?", "answer": "повышенное давление"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'flu'?", "answer": "грипп"}
{"question": "How do you say 'food poisoning' in Russian?", "answer": "пищевое отравление"}
{"question": "What is the English translation of 'насморк'?", "answer": "running nose"}
{"question": "What is the English translation of 'инфекционное заболевание'?", "answer": "infectious disease"}
{"question": "How do you say 'воспаление' in English?", "answer": "inflammation"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'wound'?", "answer": "рана"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'wound'?", "answer": "рана (rana)"}
{"question": "How do you say 'nurse' in Russian?", "answer": "медсестра (myetsistra)"}
{"question": "In Russian, what is the term for 'physician'?", "answer": "терапевт (tirapyeft)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'head'?", "answer": "голова (galava)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'heart'?", "answer": "сердце (syertse)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'kidneys'?", "answer": "почки (pochki)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation and transcription of 'tooth'?", "answer": "зуб, zup"}
{"question": "How do you say 'I feel ill' in Russian with transcription?", "answer": "Мне нездоровится, Mne nezdarovitsa"}
{"question": "Provide the Russian phrase 'Please, call an ambulance' with transcription.", "answer": "Вызовите, пожалуйста, скорую помощь, Vizavitye, pazhalusta, skoruyu pomashch"}
{"question": "What does 'Разденьтесь' mean in English?", "answer": "Undress."}
{"question": "How do you say 'Show me your tongue' in Russian?", "answer": "Покажите мне язык."}
{"question": "Translate 'Поднимите руки' to English.", "answer": "Put up your arms."}
{"question": "How do you say 'There is nothing dangerous at all!' in Russian?", "answer": "Нет ничего страшного!"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'Come to see me next week!' into Russian?", "answer": "Приходите ко мне через неделю!"}
{"question": "In Russian, how do you ask 'Where is the nearest drugstore?'", "answer": "Где ближайшая аптека?"}
{"question": "How to take these pills (drops)?", "answer": "Как принимать эти таблетки?"}
{"question": "What are the Russian translations for breakfast, dinner, and supper?", "answer": "завтрак, обед, ужин"}
{"question": "Translate 'waiter (waitress)' and 'bill' to Russian.", "answer": "официант (-ка), счет"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'bread'?", "answer": "хлеб (khlyep)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'salt'?", "answer": "соль (sol’)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'fork'?", "answer": "вилка (vilka)"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'knife'?", "answer": "нож"}
{"question": "What is the Transcription for 'napkin'?", "answer": "salfyetka"}
{"question": "What is the English translation for 'caviar'?", "answer": "caviar"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'ice-cream'?", "answer": "мороженое"}
{"question": "How do you say 'I am hungry' in Russian?", "answer": "Я проголодался"}
{"question": "What is the Belarusian word for 'juice'?", "answer": "сок"}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'avenue'?", "answer": "проспект"}
{"question": "What is the Belarusian word for 'building'?", "answer": "здание"}
{"question": "What is the Ukrainian word for 'street'?", "answer": "вулиця"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'transfer'?", "answer": "переход"}
{"question": "How do you say 'highway' in Russian?", "answer": "шоссе"}
{"question": "What does 'rush hours' translate to in Russian?", "answer": "часы «пик»"}
{"question": "Is this the right way to the park?", "answer": "Я правильно иду (еду) к парку? Ya pravil’na idu (yedu) k parku?"}
{"question": "Is it far from here?", "answer": "Далеко ли это? Daliko li eta?"}
{"question": "I’ve lost my way.", "answer": "Я заблудился. Ya zabludilsya."}
{"question": "Где ближайшая станция метро?", "answer": "Where is the nearest metro station?"}
{"question": "Где сделать пересадку на …?", "answer": "Where do I change for …?"}
{"question": "Вы выходите?", "answer": "Are you getting on?"}
{"question": "How do you say 'please' in Russian?", "answer": "пожалуйста"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'It happened this morning' in Russian?", "answer": "Это случилось сегодня утром"}
{"question": "How do you say 'I'm late' in Russian?", "answer": "я опаздываю"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'recreation'?", "answer": "отдых"}
{"question": "How do you say 'cinema' in Russian?", "answer": "кинотеатр"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'hunting' in Russian?", "answer": "охота"}
{"question": "Is there a swimming pool in the city?", "answer": "В городе есть бассейн для плавания?"}
{"question": "Which skating-ring is the best in your city?", "answer": "Какой каток в этом городе считается лучшим?"}
{"question": "I swim all the year round.", "answer": "Я плаваю круглый год"}
{"question": "What’s the charge per hour?", "answer": "Сколько это стоит в час?"}
{"question": "Where are the tennis courts?", "answer": "Где теннисные корты?"}
{"question": "Do you play …? chess draughts billiards", "answer": "Вы играете …? в шахматы в шашки в биллиард"}
{"question": "Where can I go to rest today?", "answer": "Куда можно пойти отдохнуть сегодня?"}
{"question": "Where is the recreation zone?", "answer": "Где зона отдыха?"}
{"question": "Where can we go dancing?", "answer": "Где можно потанцевать?"}
{"question": "May I invite you to dance?", "answer": "Разрешите пригласить вас на танец?"}
{"question": "Thanks. I don’t feel like dancing.", "answer": "Спасибо. Я не танцую."}
{"question": "What is the Russian word for 'cashier'?", "answer": "Кассир"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'food shop'?", "answer": "продовольственный магазин"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'market'?", "answer": "рынок, базар"}
{"question": "What is the translation of 'shop assistant'?", "answer": "продавец"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'shop window'?", "answer": "витрина"}
{"question": "What is the Ukrainian translation for 'entrance'?", "answer": "вхід"}
{"question": "What is the English translation for 'закрыто'?", "answer": "closed"}
{"question": "What is the Russian translation for 'pull'?", "answer": "к себе"}
{"question": "What is the English translation for 'сыр'?", "answer": "cheese"}
{"question": "What is the transcription for 'ягоды'?", "answer": "yagadi"}
{"question": "Where’s the nearest shop?", "answer": "Где ближайший магазин?"}
{"question": "Where do I have to pay?", "answer": "Где платить?"}
{"question": "How much does it cost?", "answer": "Сколько стоит?"}
